

CURRICULUM VITAE

Name: Naveen Chanchal

• Address: H.No-115, Pocket-21, Sector-24, Rohini, Delhi-110085.

• Mobile: 7838965250

• Email Id:naveens1786@gmail.com

Aspirations

Seeking a challenging position in a dynamic environment of fully utilize my professional and academic skills and meaningfully contribute towards organization's goal.

Experience Summary

Have over 9+ years of focused experience in IT industry. Extensive experience in development, admini stration, implementation, trouble shooting and quality management. Comprehensive experience as O racle DBA; RAC, Grid and ASM Management and 12c Software Installations, Automated Backup Imple mentation. Have good experience in LINUX administration. Have impeccable communication and inte rpersonal skills and an exceptional team player.

CERTIFICATION COMPLETED

• Oracle Certified Associate (OCA).

SKILL SET

Operating System: Linux (Red Hat 7.2/6.x)

Database: Oracle 19c, 12c, 11g, 10g on Linux and Windows

Languages: SQL

Tools: OEM 13c, Putty.

Utility: Export /Import, RMAN, Data Pump, DBCA, NETCA, NETMGR, DGMGRL.



CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Organization:

Co-orporate infotech Pvt. Ltd . From October 2020 - till.

Role : Database Administrator

Platform: Redhat Enterprise Linux 6.5, 7.2, 8.2

Key Responsibilities:

Manage the database.

Managing RAC Environment efficiently.

- Implementing and maintaining database security (create and maintain users, roles and assign privileges)
- · Configure and Managing Data Guard.
- Monitored the production Oracle alert logs for database errors.

Organization:

3i infotech Ltd. From January 2018 –October 2020. Acliv Technologies Pvt. Ltd March 2017-Dec 2017 Sanjary Corporates from Sept 2016 – Feb 2017

Client Site: Employees Provident Fund Organisation National Data Centre (EPFO)-Delhi

Role : Team Leader

Platform: Redhat Enterprise Linux 6.5, 7.2

Key Responsibilities:

- Manage the database for over 100 TB size.
- Managing RAC Environment efficiently.
- Administration of Database through OEM 13c.
- Implementing and maintaining database security (create and maintain users, roles and assign privileges)
- Managing Data Guard .
- Managed appropriate use of free space within table spaces, reclaimed space whenever possible. Reorganized tables and indexes within databases when needed.
- Monitored the production Oracle alert logs for database errors.
- Monitored system resource availability and responded to system memory and data issues.
- Replicated to a disaster recovery site for increased server manageability and availability.
- Monitor the database by collecting statistics of instance and files by querying data dictionary views.



- Advanced Backup and Recovery using Oracle's RMAN software, daily hot backups, weekly cold backups and logical backups.
- Monitoring alert log files, trace files.
- Creation and management of the batch jobs through Crontab.
- Working in 24x7 production environment and provided on-call and day-to-day support.

August-2013 - August-2016

Organisation: Jain Hydraulics Pvt. Ltd.

Client Site : Employees Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) - Chandigarh

Role : Developer Key Responsibilities:

- Installation and configuration of redhat Linux.
- User and Group Management.
- Package and patch administration.
- Managing Software installations using YUM, RPM installation.
- Disk space management using LVM.
- Scheduling Automatic Jobs through Crontab.
- Troubleshooting of day-to- day issues such as logging in, network, disk space and permission issues.
- Providing day-to- day user administration like adding or deleting users, password Policy.
- Maintaining Patches and Packages to keep the servers up to date with latest OS versions.
- Assigning permission using ACL.
- Mounting and unmounting fie systems.

September 2011 - July 2013

Organisation : AlbionInfoTel Pvt. Ltd.
Role : Assistant Service Manager

Key Responsibilities:

- Troubleshooting the general hardware/software related problems & Windows XP/2007/2008/2010.
- Administration & installation of wide range of Servers & Desktop applications.
- Installing and troubleshooting PCs and server hardware's.
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting application software's and device drivers.
- Maintenance and troubleshooting of Network connectivity.
- Installation of Networked & standalone printers & scanners.
- Attending to the Workstation Related calls.
- System Security Antivirus installation and troubleshooting.



- Extensive knowledge of hardware and software installation, configuration and maintenance.
- Operating system Installations, anti-virus updating.
- Planning, Maintaining and troubleshooting the issues related to LAN network.
- Managing & Maintaining Windows 2012 server.
- Providing technical support to clients
- Creation of AD Users.
- Group creation, modification and deletion.

ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

QUALIFICATION	COLLEGE	UNIVERSTY
MCA 2011	Gurgaon Institute of Technology & Management	Maharishi Dayanand University
B.Com 2008	Delhi University, Delhi	Delhi University, Delhi
12th, 2004	Sarvodaya Vidhalaya (Delhi)	CBSE
10th, 2002	Sarvodaya Vidhalaya (Delhi)	CBSE

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Well-honed interpersonal skills
- Self-starter, Team work
- Multitasking with focus on delivering quality output

I hereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge & belief. Date:

Place: